

# Benjamin Gray

(781) 696-2769 benjamingray85@gmail.com ben-gray.com github.com/ioncrash linkedin.com/in/benjamin-gray

Junior web developer, transitioning from several years in web editing and publishing, as well as teaching. Having completed an immersive training course at General Assembly, am looking for an opportunity to gain experience and expand my knowledge.

## **SKILLS**

- Ember
- Node.JS
- Express API
- JavaScript
- Ruby on Rails
- HTML
- CSS
- SOL
- MongoDB
- Bootstrap
- AJAX

### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

Training in full-stack development, working both individually and collaboratively in an immersive, intense environment

- Completed four web applications from concept to execution, under short time constraints
- Worked in teams to complete assignments, collaborating on development and offering support with challenges
- Worked in a number of different programming languages and modern frameworks, including Ruby on Rails and Ember
- Managed time in order to complete individual assignments and keep teams on track
- Attended class daily from 9-5, Mon-Fri, creating a close, intense working environment
- All completed projects are accessible on the internet, hosted on GitHub

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Digital Editor** (Network Awesome Magazine, 2011 – 2016)

Oversaw the development and management of an online publication, including recruiting writers, developing voice and content, digital editing and publishing.

- Managed a team of 40+ volunteer writers, including recruitment and maintaining deadlines
- Edited and published all content to the web, including handling HTML, CSS, and our proprietary CMS
- Worked closely with Creative Director and COO to determine overall direction of the publication

**Teacher** (English Language Center, 2011 – 2016)

Taught English Language to international students from all over the world

- Created original lessons and syllabi
- Worked on curriculum development for SAT and TOEFL classes
- Taught three classes a day on a variety of topics

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Art (University of Michigan 2003 - 2007)

Master of Art, Literature (Boston College 2009 - 2011)